<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>job-hunting on Jeff Stagg</title>
    <link>https://jeffstagg.com/tags/job-hunting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in job-hunting on Jeff Stagg</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyrights are a hindrance to the positive growth of society. Intellectual Property laws create an artificial scarcity by controlling supply of the product.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2022 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jeffstagg.com/tags/job-hunting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the Over-Engineered Resume</title>
      <link>https://jeffstagg.com/posts/220904-over-engineered-resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2022 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeffstagg.com/posts/220904-over-engineered-resume/</guid>
      <description>Introducing the Over-Engineered Resume A common question that comes up when a developer is fresh out of college and looking for experience is, &amp;ldquo;How can I show off a project when I haven&amp;rsquo;t done anything outside of school?&amp;rdquo; It&amp;rsquo;s a valid question, and one that we all had to face at one point. How do you get that first bit of experience to get you going?
The First Project Everyone needs a &amp;ldquo;first&amp;rdquo; project.</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introducing-the-over-engineered-resume&#34;&gt;Introducing the Over-Engineered Resume&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A common question that comes up when a developer is fresh out of college and looking for experience is, &amp;ldquo;How can I show off a project when I haven&amp;rsquo;t done anything outside of school?&amp;rdquo;
It&amp;rsquo;s a valid question, and one that we all had to face at one point. How do you get that first bit of experience to get you going?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-first-project&#34;&gt;The First Project&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone needs a &amp;ldquo;first&amp;rdquo; project. Something you can dive into, learn new things with, and something to show off your coding style. Or build one, if you&amp;rsquo;re new to programming. My first project was a portfolio. I wanted something to show off the work that I would eventually do, and I needed something to put on github (it seemed really important to me at the time).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, a decade later, I still recommend people build their own portfolio or resume. It&amp;rsquo;s a useful project to have, and I can&amp;rsquo;t count the amount of interviews I&amp;rsquo;ve been in where the team really doesn&amp;rsquo;t know how to gauge a developer to see how they would work with their team, so it&amp;rsquo;s helpful to have something to dive into with a development team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-resume&#34;&gt;The Resume&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re going to be building out a resume. Simple enough, yeah? Well, in premise, yes. The goal of a resume is simply to give an overview of your experience and skillset, and to start a conversation with a team to see if you can be productive together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project will do more than list a few keywords and try to convince a recruiter that you can bring value to their clients. I want something I can show off. I want a set of code I can be proud of to put on my public github profile. I need something I can use to play with new tech. Ever see a new tool and think &amp;ldquo;I wish I had something I could use that in&amp;rdquo;? Why not take something simple and completely over-engineer it instead?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-plan&#34;&gt;The Plan&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll be building out the Over-Engineered Resume in a series of blog posts. I&amp;rsquo;ll be using the project to demonstrate techniques that I use in my work. Follow along, and show off your skills with me!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
