<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>portfolio-building on Jeff Stagg</title>
    <link>https://jeffstagg.com/tags/portfolio-building/</link>
    <description>Recent content in portfolio-building on Jeff Stagg</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Intellectual Property laws create an artificial scarcity by controlling supply of the product.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jeffstagg.com/tags/portfolio-building/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the Over-Engineered Resume</title>
      <link>https://jeffstagg.com/posts/220904-over-engineered-resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeffstagg.com/posts/220904-over-engineered-resume/</guid>
      <description>Introducing the Over-Engineered Resume Resumes are boring, and it can be challenging to really demonstrate expertise in a craft through a document outlining your experience. Have you ever wanted to show off something with code, but all your work is zipped up behind an NDA? Ever wanted a project to hack away at and try out some new technology?
I want to build out a resume. And I don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily mean a document to email somebody in hopes I&amp;rsquo;ve said the right words to let them know I&amp;rsquo;m not an idiot and can handle their project.</description>
      <content>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introducing-the-over-engineered-resume&#34;&gt;Introducing the Over-Engineered Resume&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resumes are boring, and it can be challenging to really demonstrate expertise in a craft through a document outlining your experience. Have you ever wanted to show off something with code, but all your work is zipped up behind an NDA? Ever wanted a project to hack away at and try out some new technology?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to build out a resume. And I don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily mean a document to email somebody in hopes I&amp;rsquo;ve said the right words to let them know I&amp;rsquo;m not an idiot and can handle their project. I mean accomplishing the true goal of a resume: to demonstrate skill. I want to be able to give someone a QR code and have them bring up my resume on their device. I want to be able to screenshare during an interview and show off code, automated processes, security configurations, monitors and logs, everything you&amp;rsquo;d expect to demonstrate when showing a new team member around your software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-plan&#34;&gt;The Plan&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s decide on an MVP:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;View standard resume information
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;name / contact info&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;short bio&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;experience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;projects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;education&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multi-tiered app following CLEAN Architecture (Rob Martin) pattern&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Continuous integration / continuous deployment to cloud&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Containerized and deployed with kubernetes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can start here, and add items as we go, but this will be a baseline that we&amp;rsquo;ll strive for before we start hacking away with more features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;next-up&#34;&gt;Next Up&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ll get started by setting up repositories and building out our development environment. I want to be able to hack away on this project from any of my computers running Windows or Linux, without having to install a lot of software. Development should be convenient, and we should strive to make our environment as developer-friendly as we can.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
